## **DEBORAH DUKE**

**Phone**: 07552124180

Email: debduke10@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/deborah\_King Street, Aberdeen, AB24 3FX duke/

### RELEVANT TECHNICAL AND FIELD SKILLS

Software and IT Tools: Gained experience of manipulating large data sets using spreadsheets and conducting statistical analysis using MATLAB during my time at Swansea University and through my degree studies. Also made use of SolidWorks and ANSYS throughout my degree for design, visual ideation, modelling and feasibility assessment of an aeroplane. Gained experience using SAM to schedule and track aircraft repairs and maintenance, during my internship as an Aircraft Maintenance Engineer at Caverton Helicopters. I made use of Adobe Photoshop to edit pictures, and design logos whilst working as a part time photographer and a Creative Director. I design webpages using HTML, CSS and JavaScript during my spare time and I am currently learning Python and JavaScript in my MSc. I am confident in using a variety of IT packages in Microsoft Office.

Analysis Techniques: Data analysis, Cost-Benefit analysis, Investment appraisal.

*Group Related Qualities & Training*: Planning, scheduling, Mentoring, Time management, Sea School Leadership Training.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## July 2022-September 2022 TechX Research Intern Net-Zero Technology Centre, Aberdeen

- Provide a report on various international innovation districts and scale-up centres primarily in the clean energy sector to highlight the best practices that can be adapted to the Energy Transmission Zone (ETZ) project in Aberdeen
- Research companies related to TechX focus areas to approach to gain customer network for pioneers during cohorts.
- Research deep tech ventures to approach to partner with and promote TechX cohorts
- Reviewed TechX online portal and assessed features that can be implemented to improve the contents and user experience of the portal.

## March 2021 – June 2021 Compliance Intern

## First City Monument Bank (FCMB)

- Identified and analysed the rules governing the operations of the bank to create a robust compliance universe
- Monitored adequacy of controls to ensure compliance with regulatory requirements.
- Ensured legal applicability and enforceability of FCMB's information security policies, standards and procedures.

# **Sept 2019 - Sept 2020 Lead Creative Director**

#### Crew Model, Swansea

- Required to direct creative management and develop a strong incentive based work environment.
- Brand management across all social media platforms. Have overseen an increase in publicity since taking the role.
- Designed and implemented concepts, guidelines and strategies in various creative projects and oversaw them to completion. Liaise with prospective clientele, collaborative partners & new models.
- Set creative direction and agenda for the creative team to effectively launch new projects.

## Feb 2019 – May 2019. Aircraft Maintenance Engineer Intern

# **Caverton Helicopters**

- Installation of helicopter control panels for private aviation and logistic company.
- Worked on assembly and dismantling of nickel-cadmium batteries.
- Trained in SAM; a software used to monitor helicopters and alerts the engineers when repairs are needed.
- Carried out routine safety inspections on commercial helicopters.
- Installed main rotor and tail rotor blade of a helicopter.
- Understood the dynamics of the storage sector.
- Arranged the parts to an assigned section both physically and electronically.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Jan 2022 – Present. MSc Information

#### **University of Aberdeen Technology**

This skills-based program, taught by internationally renowned lecturers, researchers, and specialists in their fields, gives students the theoretical understanding and practical experience of implementing computer science ideas in real-world situations.

Courses include: Introduction to programming, Advanced Programming, Fundamentals of Software Project Management, Enterprise Software Development, Web Development, Information Security, Database Systems and Big Data, Human Computer Interaction.

Dissertation title: TBD

# Nov 2017 - July 2020 BEng Aerospace Engineering

## **Swansea University**

Studied a broad range of subjects including: Aerodynamics, Thermodynamics, Fluid Mechanics,

Engineering Design, Computer Aided Engineering, Engineering Professional Development, Flight Mechanics, Aerospace Control Systems, High Performance Materials and Selection, Airframe Structures.

Final Year Group Project: Design a Hybrid Business jet.

Final Year Individual Project: Smart Materials and Aerofoil Optimization.

## **Cambridge International Examination (IGCSE)**

**S.T.T.R College** Mathematics **A**,

Chemistry B, English as a second Language B, Biology C, Physics C

#### OTHER POSTIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY AND LEADERSHIP

## 2018- 2020 Volunteer worker at Place of Victory Church (RCCG):

- Head the media department and worked in the choir department.
- Assist with online presence and handling churches social media platforms.
- In charge of photography, video work, sound and audio in the church.

#### 2018-2020 Student Ambassador for Swansea University

• Assist the College of Engineering during undergraduate and postgraduate open-days. • Give tours during open days and interact with potential students and families.

## 2017-2018 Treasurer and Mentor in the Women's Engineering society Swansea University

- In charge of the societies finances and mentored female engineering students (fresher's) who required settling in.
- Encourage and interact with future female engineering students in the university.

## **REFERENCES**

Dr. Kiyo Wada; Supervisor, k.wada@swansea.ac.uk (Other references are available on request).